<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="PF">
    <!-- Vanara Race -->
    <race>
        <name>Vanara</name>
        <ability>Dex 2</ability>
        <ability>Wis 2</ability>
        <ability>Cha -2</ability>
        <size>M</size>
        <speed>30</speed>
        <trait>
            <name>Languages</name>
            <text>Vanaras begin play speaking Common and Vanaran. Vanaras with high Intelligence scores can choose from the following: Aklo, Celestial, Elven, Gnome, Goblin, and Sylvan.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Nimble</name>
            <text>Vanaras have a +2 racial bonus on Acrobatics and Stealth checks.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Acrobatics +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Stealth +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Prehensile Tail:</name>
            <text>A vanara has a long, flexible tail that she can use to carry objects. She cannot wield weapons with her tail, but the tail allows her to retrieve a small, stowed object carried on her person as a swift action.</text>
        </trait>
        <!-- Alternate Racial Traits -->
        <trait>
            <name>Acrobatic (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Vanaras are often extraordinarily agile, capable of dancing around slower-moving humans with playful grace. They gain a +2 racial bonus on Acrobatics and Escape Artist checks. This racial trait replaces nimble.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Acrobatics +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Escape Artist +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Change Size (Su) (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>One vanara in every 500 is gifted with limited shapeshifting ability. Such a creature can adjust her size at will. She gains the change shape ability and the shapeshifter subtype. Instead of changing appearance, she can use change shape to reduce her size category to Small. Her ability scores don’t change, only her size (and thus her weapon damage); normal size penalties and bonuses to AC and CMD and on attack and skill rolls apply. Changing size or returning to her true size is a full-round action. This racial trait alters the vanara’s type and replaces nimble.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Risky Troublemaker (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some vanaras can choose to roll twice on Use Magic Device checks. If they do, they take the higher result unless either die roll is a natural 1, in which case the check automatically fails. This racial trait replaces prehensile tail.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Tree Stranger (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some vanaras have spent their lives among humans in centers of learning instead of traditional treetop homes. These vanaras treat all Knowledge skills as class skills, but lose their climb speed racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Whitecape (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>The rare whitecape vanara clans have more in common with savanna-dwelling baboons than the jungle-dwelling monkeys that most vanaras resemble. Their stooping build grants them a +4 racial bonus to CMD when resisting a bull rush or trip. These vanaras usually have a thick mane of hair on the head and shoulders (called a “cape”) and shorter tails. This racial trait replaces prehensile tail.</text>
        </trait>
    </race>
</compendium>