<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="PF">
    <!-- Drow Race -->
    <race>
        <name>Drow</name>
        <ability>Dex 2</ability>
        <ability>Cha 2</ability>
        <ability>Con -2</ability>
        <size>M</size>
        <speed>30</speed>
        <trait>
            <name>Languages</name>
            <text>Drow begin play speaking Elven and Undercommon. Drow with high Intelligence scores can choose from the following languages: Abyssal, Aklo, Aquan, Common, Draconic, Drow Sign Language, Gnome, or Goblin.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Weapon Familiarity</name>
            <text>Drow are proficient with the hand crossbow, rapier, and shortsword.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Immunities</name>
            <text>Drow are immune to magic sleep effects and gain a +2 racial bonus on saving throws against enchantment spells and effects.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spell Resistance</name>
            <text>Drow possess spell resistance (SR) equal to 6 plus their total number of class levels.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Keen Senses</name>
            <text>Drow gain a +2 racial bonus on Perception checks.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Perception +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spell-Like Abilities (Su)</name>
            <text>Drow can cast dancing lights, darkness, and faerie fire, once each per day, using their total character level as caster level.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Poison Use</name>
            <text>Drow are skilled in the use of poisons and never risk accidentally poisoning themselves.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Superior Darkvision</name>
            <text>Drow have superior darkvision, allowing them to see perfectly in the dark up to 120 feet.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Light Blindness</name>
            <text>As deep underground dwellers naturally, drow suffer from light blindness. Abrupt exposure to any bright light blinds drow for 1 round. On subsequent rounds, they are dazzled as long as they remain in the affected area.</text>
        </trait>
        <!-- Alternate Racial Traits -->
        <trait>
            <name>Ambitious Schemer (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Seduction and treachery are tools for advancement in drow society, even for the martially inclined. Drow with this racial trait may choose either Bluff or Diplomacy as a class skill, and gain a +2 bonus on such skill checks. This racial trait replaces keen senses.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Ancestral Grudge (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>The enmity between the drow and elves and dwarves is long-standing and deeply entrenched. Drow with this racial trait gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against humanoids with the dwarf or elf subtypes (with the exception of drow) because of their special training against these reviled foes. This racial trait replaces poison use.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Blasphemous Covenant (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Since their twisted beginnings, the drow have consorted with demons. Some drow have strong ties with these creatures and may call upon ancient and obscene associations to sway demonic cooperation. Drow with this racial trait gain a +2 bonus on Diplomacy checks made against unbound creatures with the demon subtype. Furthermore, demons conjured with any summon spell gain +2 hit points per Hit Die. Lastly, the cost of bribes or offerings for any planar ally spell cast by these drow to summon a demon is reduced by 20%. This racial trait replaces keen senses and poison use.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Champion of Dark Powers (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some drow offer themselves to dark patrons, particularly demon lords. Drow with this racial trait apply their spell resistance only against spells with the good or healing descriptor or against spells cast by a divine spellcaster who worships a good-aligned deity. Anytime a drow with this racial trait casts a spell with the evil descriptor, the DC to resist the spell’s effects increases by 2. This modifies the spell resistance racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Defensive Training (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Many drow cities are frequently beset by attacks from aberrations, prompting the residents train themselves to defend against them. Drow gain a +4 dodge bonus to AC against aberrations. This racial trait replaces drow immunities, keen senses, and poison use.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Poison Minion (4 RP) (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Drow sometimes augment their slaves and frontline warriors by making them toxic, causing their bodies to internally produce mawbane poison (see below). The resulting poisonous creature makes a potent weapon in the effort to discourage neighboring monsters. Any creature that hits such a character with a bite attack is immediately exposed to its poison. The save DC for this poison is equal to 10 + 1/2 the character’s Hit Dice + the character’s Constitution modifier. Mawbane Poison—ingested; save Fortitude as above; frequency 1/round for 4 rounds; effect 1d2 Constitution damage; cure 1 save. Drow can take this trait in place of drow immunities, light blindness, spell resistance, and weapon familiarity.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Seducer (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Certain drow possess an innate understanding of the darkest desires that lurk in every heart. Drow with this racial trait add +1 to the saving throw DCs for spells and spell-like abilities of the enchantment school. In addition, drow with a Wisdom score of 15 or higher may use charm person once per day as a spell-like ability (caster level equal to the drow’s character level). This racial trait replaces drow immunities.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Stalker (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>The lands outside of drow cities, from rough-hewn tunnels to rocky caverns, are treacherous to navigate. Drow with this racial trait may move through difficult terrain without penalty while underground. In addition, drow with a Dexterity of 13 or higher gain Nimble Moves as a bonus feat. This racial trait replaces the spell-like abilities racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sure Step (2 RP) (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Adventurers can spend their whole careers in the alleys and sewers of large cities or the tunnels of the Underworld. Characters with this trait suffer no movement penalties when blinded or moving in darkness. Drow can take this trait in place of keen senses.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Surface Infiltrator (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some drow dwell close to the surface lands, either because they serve drow causes or they were exiled. Drow with this racial trait gain low-light vision, allowing them to see twice as far as humans in conditions of dim light. This racial trait replaces the darkvision and light blindness racial traits.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Underworld Guide (2 RP) (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Those who brave the lightless tunnels below the world’s surface learn to identify the dangerous phenomena that characterize the Underworld. Characters with this trait gain a +2 bonus on initiative checks, and on saves against traps and hazards when underground (from a lifetime of dodging accursed pools, cave-ins, and green slime). Drow can take this trait in place of keen senses.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Voice in the Darkness (2 RP) (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Prerequisite(s): Charisma 13+</text>
            <text>Characters who practice coercion and intimidation in the Underworld or on the Shadow Plane learn to do so in dim light or no light at all. As long as they are in dim light or darker conditions, characters with this trait gain a +2 bonus on Intimidate and Stealth checks. Drow can take this trait in place of weapon familiarity.</text>
        </trait>
    </race>
</compendium>