<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="PF">
    <!-- Fetchling  Race -->
    <race>
        <name>Fetchling </name>
        <ability>Dex 2</ability>
        <ability>Cha 2</ability>
        <ability>Wis -2</ability>
        <size>M</size>
        <speed>30</speed>
        <trait>
            <name>Languages</name>
            <text>Fetchlings begin play speaking Common. Fetchlings with a high Intelligence scores can choose from the following: Aklo, Aquan, Auran, Draconic, D’ziriak (understanding only, cannot speak), Ignan, Terran, and any regional human tongue.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Shadow Blending (Su)</name>
            <text>Attacks against a fetchling in dim light have a 50% miss chance instead of the normal 20% miss chance. This ability does not grant total concealment; it just increases the miss chance.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Shadowy Resistance</name>
            <text>Fetchlings have cold resistance 5 and electricity resistance 5.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Skilled</name>
            <text>Fetchlings have a +2 racial bonus on Knowledge (planes) and Stealth checks.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Knowledge (planes) +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Stealth +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Spell-Like Abilities (Sp)</name>
            <text>A fetchling can use disguise self once per day as a spell-like ability. He can assume the form of any humanoid creature. A fetchling’s caster level is equal to his total Hit Dice. When a fetchling reaches 9th level in any combination of classes, he gains shadow walk (self only) as a spell-like ability usable once per day as a spell-like ability. A fetchling’s caster level is equal to his total Hit Dice. When a fetchling reaches 13th level in any combination of classes, he gains plane shift (self only, to the Shadow Plane or the Material Plane only) usable once per day as a spell-like ability. A fetchling’s caster level is equal to his total Hit Dice.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Darkvision</name>
            <text>Fetchlings can see perfectly in the dark up to 60 feet.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Low-Light Vision</name>
            <text>In addition to their ability to see perfectly in the dark up to 60 ft, fetchlings have low-light vision, allowing them to see twice as far as humans in conditions of dim light.</text>
        </trait>
        <!-- Alternate Racial Traits -->
        <trait>
            <name>Bound to Here (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some fetchlings are from families that have fearfully avoided the Shadow Plane, living on the Material Plane for generations. As a result, these fetchlings are closely tied to the Material Plane. Fetchlings with this racial trait count as outsiders with the native subtype and humanoids with the human subtype for any effect related to race, including feat prerequisites and spells that affect humanoids. They can pass for human without using the Disguise skill. This racial trait replaces the +2 racial bonus on Knowledge (planes) checks from the skilled racial trait, and alters the native outsider racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Boundary Walker (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some fetchlings deftly navigate between the worlds of shadow and light. A fetchling with this racial trait gains spell resistance equal to 5 + his character level against spells and spell-like abilities with the light or shadow descriptors, as well as spells and spell-like abilities of the illusion (shadow) subschool. This racial trait replaces the shadow blending and shadowy resistance racial traits.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Deep Shadow Explorer (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Fetchlings who widely explore the Shadow Plane learn to confront fearsome things best left undescribed. Fetchlings with this racial trait gain a +2 racial bonus on all saves against fear effects. This racial trait replaces the skilled racial trait. </text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Emissary (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Rare fetchlings excel in the role of emissary between the Shadow Plane and the Material Plane. Once per day, such a fetchling can roll twice when making a Bluff or Diplomacy check and take the better roll. This racial trait replaces shadow blending.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Gloom Shimmer (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some fetchlings can manipulate shadowy energy in order to displace their location instead of transporting between shadows. Upon reaching 9th level, instead of gaining shadow walk as a spell-like ability, these fetchlings gain displacement as a spell-like ability usable twice per day. For this ability, a fetchling’s caster level is equal to his total Hit Dice. This racial trait modifies the spell-like ability racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Recluse (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some fetchlings learn how to deflect unwanted attention. Fetchlings with this racial trait can use sanctuary once per day as a spell-like ability. When such a fetchling reaches 9th level in any combination of classes, he gains nondetection (self only) as a spell-like ability usable once per day, and at 13th level, he gains veil (self only) usable once per day. A fetchling’s caster level is equal to his total Hit Dice. This racial trait modifies the fetchling’s spell-like abilities racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Shadow Agent (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Families of fetchlings make their livings serving as agents, diplomats, and spies mediating between humans and the powers of the Plane of Shadow. They gain a +2 racial bonus on Bluff and Diplomacy checks. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Shadow Magic (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Fetchlings who spend their time studying the subtle magic of their adopted plane gain arcane insights on the use of shadow spells. These fetchlings gain a +1 racial bonus to the DC of any illusion (shadow) spells they cast. This racial trait replaces the skilled racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Subtle Manipulator (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Rather than taking on the forms of others, some fetchling are adept at destroying the memories of other creatures. Instead of gaining disguise self as a spell-like ability, such fetchlings can use memory lapse once per day as a spell-like ability. For this ability, a fetchling’s caster level is equal to his total Hit Dice. This racial trait modifies the spell-like ability racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Umbral Escort (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some fetchlings descend from talented planar travelers who dwelled in the dark places between worlds and could conduct others across the planes. A fetchling with this racial trait loses the disguise self spell-like ability, but his shadow walk and plane shift spell-like abilities need not affect himself only. This racial trait replaces the low-light vision racial trait and modifies the spell-like abilities racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Unnerving Gaze (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some fetchlings gain an upsetting gaze attack that they can activate three times per day as a standard action, affecting all creatures within a 30-foot cone that can see. All creatures that meet the fetchling’s unnerving gaze are shaken for 1 round (DC = 10 + 1/2 the fetchling’s character level + her Charisma modifier; Will negates). When the fetchling reaches 9th level, her gaze instead causes creatures to be staggered. When the fetchling reaches 13th level, her gaze instead causes creatures to be stunned. Unnerving gaze is a mind-affecting fear effect. This racial trait replaces the fetchling’s spell-like abilities.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Whispers from Shadow (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Fetchlings are known for wheeling and dealing. A fetchling with this racial trait gains a +4 racial bonus on Bluff checks when he tells a lie and wants to convince an opponent that what he is saying is true. This racial trait replaces the skilled racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>World Walker (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Fetchlings who have spent most of their lives on the Material Plane can become more acclimated to their new environments. Instead of gaining a +2 racial bonus on Knowledge (planes) checks, these fetchlings gain a +1 racial bonus on Knowledge (nature) and Knowledge (local) checks. This racial trait modifies the skilled racial trait.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Knowledge (nature) +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Knowledge (local) +2</modifier>
        </trait>
    </race>
</compendium>