<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="PF">
    <!-- Goblin Race -->
    <race>
        <name>Goblin</name>
        <ability>Dex 4</ability>
        <ability>Str -2</ability>
        <ability>Cha -2</ability>
        <size>S</size>
        <speed>30</speed>
        <trait>
            <name>Languages</name>
            <text>Goblins begin play speaking Goblin. Goblins with high Intelligence scores can choose from the following: Common, Draconic, Dwarven, Gnoll, Gnome, Halfling, and Orc.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Skilled</name>
            <text>Goblins gain a +4 racial bonus on Ride and Stealth checks.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Ride +4</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Stealth +4</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Fast Movement</name>
            <text>Goblins gain a +10 foot bonus to their base speed (this is already added to their Base Speed.)</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Darkvision</name>
            <text>Goblins see perfectly in the dark up to 60 feet.</text>
        </trait>
        <!-- Alternate Racial Traits -->
        <trait>
            <name>Cave Crawler (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some goblins are born and raised in caves and rarely see the light of day. Goblins with this trait gain a climb speed of 10 feet and the +8 racial bonus on Climb checks associated with having a climb speed. Goblins with this racial trait have a base speed of 20 feet and lose the fast movement racial trait.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>City Scavenger (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Goblins who live within the boundaries of human cities survive by scavenging for refuse and hunting stray animals. Goblins with this trait gain a +2 racial bonus on Perception and Survival checks, and can use Survival to forage for food while in a city. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Perception +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Survival +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Eat Anything (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Raised with little or no proper food, many goblins have learned to survive by eating whatever they happen across and can digest nearly anything without getting sick. Goblins with this trait gain a +4 on Survival checks to forage for food and a +4 racial bonus on saves versus effects that cause the nauseated or sickened conditions. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Hard Head, Big Teeth (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Goblins are known for their balloon-like heads and enormous maws, but some have even more exaggeratedly large heads filled with razor-sharp teeth. Goblins with this trait gain a bite attack as a primary natural attack that deals 1d4 points of damage. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Junk Tinker (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Goblins use ramshackle equipment and vehicles that seem like they should never function. Goblins gain a +2 racial bonus on driving checks and on Craft checks to build or repair weapons or vehicles without the proper tools. They can make the attempt with any material that can hold the right shape for a few uses, but normally unfit materials produce items with the fragile quality. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Ride +4</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Craft +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Over-Sized Ears (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>While goblins’ ears are never dainty, these goblins have freakishly large ears capable of picking up even the smallest sounds. Goblins with this racial trait gain a +4 bonus on Perception checks. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Perception +4</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Tree Runner (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>In trackless rain forests and marshes, it can be difficult to find dry ground to build on. goblin tribes living in such areas have learned to live in the treetops. These goblins gain a +4 racial bonus on Acrobatics and Climb checks. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Acrobatics +4</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Climb +4</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Weapon Familiarity (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Goblins’ traditional weapons are the dogslicer and the horsechopper, weapons designed specifically to bring down their most hated foes. Goblins with this trait are proficient with the dogslicer and the horsechopper, and treat any weapon with the word “goblin” in it as martial weapons. This racial trait replaces skilled.</text>
        </trait>
    </race>
</compendium>
