<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="PF">
    <!-- Hobgoblin Race -->
    <race>
        <name>Hobgoblin</name>
        <ability>Dex 2</ability>
        <ability>Con 2</ability>
        <size>M</size>
        <speed>30</speed>
        <trait>
            <name>Languages</name>
            <text>Hobgoblins begin play speaking Common and Goblin. Hobgoblins with high Intelligence scores can choose from the following: Draconic, Dwarven, Infernal, Giant, and Orc.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Sneaky</name>
            <text>Hobgoblins receive a +4 racial bonus on Stealth checks.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Stealth +4</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Darkvision</name>
            <text>Hobgoblins can see perfectly in the dark up to 60 feet.</text>
        </trait>
        <!-- Alternate Racial Traits -->
        <trait>
            <name>Authoritative (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Hobgoblins often develop a knack for controlling others. They gain a +2 racial bonus on Diplomacy and Intimidate checks. Both skills are always class skills for them. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Diplomacy +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Intimidate +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Bandy-Legged (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Bandy-legged hobgoblins have an even more exaggerated stature than other hobgoblins, with bowed legs and massive shoulders. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain a +2 racial bonus on Climb and Ride checks, and a +2 racial bonus to their CMD against bull rush or trip attempts while on solid ground. The base speed of bandy-legged hobgoblins is reduced to 20 feet.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Climb +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Ride +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Battle-Hardened (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Incessant drills make defense second nature to some hobgoblins. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain a +1 bonus to CMD. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
            <modifier category = "bonus">Combat Maneuver Defense +1</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Engineer (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>hobgoblin engineers tinker endlessly with fire, explosives, and the engines of war. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain a +2 racial bonus on Craft (alchemy) and Knowledge (engineering) checks. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Knowledge (engineering) +2</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Craft (alchemy) +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Fearsome (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Some hobgoblins scorn caution and subtlety for swagger and bluster. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain a +4 racial bonus on Intimidate checks. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Intimidate +4</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Magehunter (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Hobgoblins hate and fear arcane casters. A magehunter gains a +2 racial bonus on Spellcraft checks made to identify a spell being cast and a +1 racial bonus on attack rolls against arcane spellcasters. He only gains this bonus against creatures that use spells, and not against those that only use spell-like abilities. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Pit Boss (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Slave blood fuels the hobgoblin war machine. Pit bosses extract the last breath of labor from their charges with a liberal touch of the lash. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain proficiency with whips and a +1 racial bonus on combat maneuver checks made to disarm or trip with a whip. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Scarred (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>A hobgoblin can scar himself with both blade and fire to toughen his hide into a mass of horny scars. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain a +1 natural armor bonus to Armor Class. However, the repeated exposure to fire permanently damages their eyes. This racial trait replaces the darkvision racial trait.</text>
            <modifier category = "bonus">Natural Armor +1</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Slave Hunter (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Hobgoblin slavers excel at tracking down runaway slaves and surviving in filthy conditions. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain a +2 racial bonus on Survival checks and a +2 racial bonus on Fortitude saves against disease. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Survival +2</modifier>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>Unfit (Alternate Racial Traits)</name>
            <text>Hobgoblins who failed to secure a position in the military hold the lowest status in hobgoblin society, and quickly learn the value of currying favor with their betters. Hobgoblins with this racial trait gain proficiency in a single martial weapon and +1 racial bonus on Bluff and Diplomacy checks. This racial trait replaces sneaky.</text>
            <modifier category = "skill">Bluff +1</modifier>
            <modifier category = "skill">Diplomacy +1</modifier>
        </trait>
    </race>
</compendium>
